# Filippo Maria Raeli

# GIS Specialist | Web Developer | Urban Planner |



(+39) 349-6013778 filippo.raeli@gmail.com LinkedIn

# SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Over the past 10 years, I have had an extensive experience in managing nautical/urban cartographic data by GIS. This includes proficient use of all ESRI and Open Source products to analyze and create layers from remote sensing imagery, shapefiles, and census data. This is only a short list of materials and products I am able to manipulate and create for a wide range of client needs.

As a person, I believe that it is important for people to develop personal growth.

Recently, I have strongly completed the 1st level Master's degree in Cyber Security to improve my knowledge.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# GIS Consultant | Freelancer | Italy | From May 2018 to present

I worked for an international solar developer identifying the key planning constraints in Italy.

I wrote articles for ScribbleMaps.com.

I created cool graphic map for Rome.

# GIS Specialist | Navionics | Italy | From Jan 2011 to Apr 2017

Throughout my professional career, I have worked at Navionics. I had the pleasure of facing challenging opportunities that helped me to experience different projects. Over the years, I have developed and gained knowledge of implementing new strategies and I have been exposed to a variety of methods to sort out different tasks.

The most important activities can be summarized as below:

#### • Chart checks in order to put them on the market:

I checked many charts related to special projects, i.e. RFC, Garmin, P-routes, US-S57, Sweden and Norway S57, etc.

I have done an important support on Sonar charts checks highlighting important and systemic issues.

Finally, I strongly support the team in order to manage the charts checks in the faster way thanks to my consolidate knowledge on GIS software.

## • Development and Management of dynamic reports to monitor different projects and teams:

HUB & NT Chart; Chart QC Productivity Rate; Sonar Productivity Rate; P-Routes Productivity Rate; RPD Changes HUB Chart Reject Rate (PnP Charts); P+ & OEM HUB Chart Reject Rate (PnP Charts); DRs Resolution Time; RFC DB NT Reject Rate; CUP DB NT Reject Rate; Source NT Reject Rate; CUP & CUP QC Productivity Rate; RFC Productivity Rate.

#### • Management of Discrepancy Report sent by the customers

I have managed and sorted out many Reports in according to new needs working with PostgreSQL. I checked many Tiles&PnPs related to DRs during HUB checks especially in high season to remove the backlog.

#### • Management and Implementation of the chart files in order to release them to the market:

This activity was extremely complex due to both manual action and the enormous amount of data to upload.

In the same way, I monitored the files coming from NPS by GIS tool and SQL queries in order to send daily summary report.

I have managed the first Europe mobile coverage released by NPS for the entire cycle.

# GIS Analyst | University of Florence | Italy | From Apr 2008 to Mar 2009

Development of a database for monitoring the urban growth in Tuscany. Data was captured from different and official historical sources.

# GIS Coordinator | Pontedera Municipality | Italy | From Apr 2005 to Feb 2009

Numbering of buildings and census houses and updating / preparation of layout map.

Implementation, updating and maintenance of the geodatabase.

Configuration of WebGIS interfaces applied to Urbanistic, Tourism and Civil Protection.

# Data Entry | CIHEAM Bari | Bari - Italy | From Oct 2002 to Jun 2003

Implementation of a database for monitoring bio-agricultural companies in the Puglia region.

### **EDUCATION**

# 1st level Master degree in Cyber Security

# | Pisa University | Italy | From Apr 2017 to Mar 2018

Networking, Data mining, Web technology.

Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network security & Ethical hacking, Operating Systems Security, Digital forensics, Cyber intelligence, Large scale network analysis, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity. Laboratory of Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Laboratory of cyber security and risk monitoring for networks and applications, Laboratory of secure application development (network, mobile, cloud).

# Bachelor's degree in Planning the City of the Territory and Landscape

# | Florence University | Italy | From Oct 2003 to Jul 2007

I analyzed and understand the settlements and territorial structures in interdisciplinary terms and to work on them through the conscious application of the planning tools with the degree of competence commensurate with the three-year degree.

Traineeships at local authorities and the degree thesis on the Web Map Application in urban planning complete the study program and the training course.

#### **SKILLS**

**QGIS** => Focused on creating several courses with the aim to manage python scripts.

**ArcGIS** => Utilized this software at the beginning of my bachelor's degree studies and creatively developed many projects.

**SQL** => I manage and sort out many statistic reports through PostgreSQL and MySQL.

**Database** => Made important and effective contributions to the analysis data process.

**HTML&CSS&PHP** => Updated and implemented pages and back-end using HTML, CSS and PHP for a website in the CMS WordPress I can manage and sort out

**Python** => During the development of Cyber Security, I created several diverse projects targeted with different scopes/focuses.

**JavaScript** => Rewrite existing code, and add new code on top of pre-existing code.

**Graphic and Web Designer** => Develop websites, print and web marketing materials such as brochures, posters, and logos using Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and CorelDraw.

**Salesforce** => I managed the multi-functional platform that serves to create several statistic reports and an online interface that deals with customer needs.

**MS office** => Utilized in every day to day operation from creating basic word documents to complicated excel sheets/algorithms.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English – Upper Intermediate - CEFR Level B2 - Aug 2018

Six years of face-to-face interaction in the Navionics company and I effectively responded to oral and written communication while simultaneously responding to the concerns and needs of the global partners from India and the US.

Italian - Native.

### **CERTIFICATIONS & MEMBERSHIPS**

- Data Scientist Nanodegree Program in progress.
- Creating a Map with Illustrator Jan 2019.
- Earth Imagery at Work MOOC- Dec 2018.
- Maps with R Leaflet Nov 2018.
- Do-It-Yourself Geo Apps MOOC Oct 2018.
- Using Open Source Tools to Create an Enterprise GIS Oct 2018.
- Basics of JavaScript Web Apps Jul 2018.
- Cartography MOOC Jun 2018.
- Leaflet for Beginners Jun 2018.
- Complete Elasticsearch Masterclass with Logstash and Kibana May 2018.
- Introduction to **QGIS Python** Programming May 2018.
- Build and Host Your Own LAMP Web Server April 2018.
- Internet Mapping with Geoserver, Postgres, and Openlayers 3 April 2018.
- Introduction to **GDAL** April 2018.
- The Complete Web Developer Course 2.0 Mar 2018.
- Web Application penetration testing and Bug Bounty Course Jan 2018.
- The Complete Nmap Ethical Hacking Course: Network Security Dec 2017.
- Complete **Python Bootcamp**: Go from zero to hero in Python Aug 2017.
- QGIS python course Mar 2017.
- QGIS advanced course Dec 2016.
- PostGIS introduction Oct 2012.
- PostgreSQL Immersion Oct 2012.
- GIS site analysis Apr 2011.
- **INSPIRE** May 2010.
- **Pmapper** Apr 2008.
- Boating driving license beyond 12miles Sep 1998.